Guide to the Records of the NYU Abu Dhabi Institute AD.RG.024.1
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
- Audiovisual Event Files (Conferences and Programs), 2007-2015
  - AY 2010-2011
    - Beyond the Crash: Overcoming the First Crisis of Globalisation, Feb. 24, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: The Right Honorable Gordon Brown MP, Bruce Jones
    - The US, Emerging Powers, and Traditional Threats, Feb. 25-26, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Bruce Jones
    - The Theif of Baghdad, Feb. 26, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers:
    - Obama's Health Reform: Is It Doomed? (And What About His Presidency?), Feb. 27, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Rogan Kersh; Robert Shrum; Diane Yu
    - Use and Misuse of Probability, Mar. 1, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Nassim Taleb
    - Chaos - Theater Mitu, Mar. 02-05, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Ruben Polendo
    - Housing Middle Income Households in High-Cost Cities: Is There a Role for Government?, Mar. 3, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Micheal White; Talal Al Dhiyebi; Ingrid Gould Ellen
    - Long Distance Networks and World Systems, Mar. 6-7, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Barbara Kowalzig; Walter Scheidel
    - Beliefs, Markets and Empires, Mar. 6-7, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Andrew Monson, Walter Scheidel
    - Commerce and Empire in India: the Centrality of the Hindu Temple, Mar. 7, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: David Ludden
    - Enhancing Economic Development Through Technology, Mar. 8, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Yaw Nyarko, Lakshminarayanan Subramanian
    - The Center for Technology and Economic Development (CTED) Conference, Mar. 08, 2011 (Box E-records)
    - On Literature, Love, and Revolution in the Arab World, Mar. 10, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Ibrahim Abdel Meguid; Mohamed Al Mansi Kandeel; Rabai Al Madhoun, Muhamed Osman Al Khalil
    - The 'Heart and Mind' of Diplomacy: Twenty-First Century Cultural Diplomacy, Mar. 13, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Cynthia Schneider
    - Moments in Silence: The Authentic Literary Narratives of the Iran-Iraq War (1980-1988), Mar. 15-17, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Mohammad Mehdi Khorrami, Shouleh Vatanabadi
    - The Stock Market and Corporate Investment, Mar. 16, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Alexander Ljungqvist
    - Women Writers of the Middle East, Mar. 19, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Haifa Zangana, Gloria Jacobs, Judith Miller
    - The Magic of Words, Mar. 28, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Anna Deavere Smith; Ruben Polendo
    - Completing the Urbanization Project, Apr. 3, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Paul Romer
    - Markets: A Novel Approach to Assess Sovereign Debt Risk, Apr. 4, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Ed Altman
    - Moufida Talatil Tunisie, Apr. 9, 2011 (Box E-records)
    - Nationalization of the Workforce in the GCC Countries II, Apr. 10-11, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Samira Al. Atallah
    - Healthcare Reform in the US, Apr. 11, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Delos Cosgrove, Andrew Rubin
    - Are Toleration and Neutrality Compatible Ideas? [The Non-Obsolesence of Toleration], Apr. 14, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Catriona McKinnon
    - Intel Labs: Staying Ahead of Technology, Apr. 18, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Tanay Karnik
    - 3D Integration Workshop for High Performance Computing Systems, Apr. 18-19, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Hai (Helen) Li, Yuan Xie, H. Jonathan Chao
    - Imagining the Future: New Worlds, New Arts, New Models, Apr. 21-22, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Anna Deavere Smith, Gordon Lester
    - A Conversation with Khaled Abol Naga, Apr. 20, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Philip Kennedy, Khaled Abol Naga
    - Zeb & Haniya, Merlijn Twaalfhoven, and Anani Dodji Sanouvi, Apr. 21, 2011 (Box E-records)
    - Unifying Arab Awakening, Apr. 20, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Khaled Abol Naga
    - Salut Cousin!, Apr. 23, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Peter Scarlet, Ella Shohat, Robert Stam, Mo Ogrodnik
    - Women's Voices in the Muslim World, Apr. 28, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Anne Rasmussen; Walter Zev
    - Classical and Quantum Turbulence, May 2-5, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: K.R. Sreenivasan, Victor S. L'vov, Ladislav Skrbek, William F. Vinen
    - From Angstroms to Light Years, May 02, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: K.R. Sreenivasan
    - A Bicycle Built for Two: Humans and Computers Making Music Together, May 4, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Rebecca Fiebrink
    - Le Grand Voyage, May 7, 2011 (Box E-records)
    - The Body as a Weapon: Understanding Suicide Bombing, May 8, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Riaz Hassan
    - Translating Shafi's Risala, May 10, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Joseph E. Lowry
    - Aspects of Hadhrami Migration in Southeast Asia, May 31, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Michael Gilsenan
  - AY 2011-2012
    - A Decade Lost: Locating Gender in US Counter-Terrorism, Sept. 19, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Lama Fakih; Jayne Huckerby; Sari Kouvo, Rahma Abdulkadir
    - Gender, National Security, and Counterterrorism, Sept. 19-20, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Margaret Satterthwaite, Jayne Huckerby
    - Law and Literature: Portia's Brilliant Legal Strategy, Sept. 22, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Stephen Gillers
    - A Cosmopolitan Pantheon: Panel Paintings From Roman Egypt, Sept. 27, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Thomas F. Mathews
    - An Egyptian Pantheon at the Origin of European Painting, Sept. 28, 2011 (Box E-records)
    - Film Screening of "Khan Al Khalili", Oct. 6, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: In collaboration with Abu Dhabi Film Festival
    - What the Global Economy Needs, Oct. 9, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: The Right Honorable Gordon Brown MP; Bruce D. Jones
    - The Obesity/Diabetes Threat and the Rise of Surgical Treatment, Oct. 12, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Philip Schauer
    - A Bottom-Up Approach to the Rebuilding of Somalia: The Azania Case, Oct. 17, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Mohamed Abdi Gandhi, Ken Menkhaus
    - The Undispossessed Photographs by Yasser Alwan, Oct. 20, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Shamoon Zamir, Yasser Alwan
    - Muslim Americans: Faith, Freedom, and the Future, Oct. 23, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Angela Migally; Dalia Mogahed; Jamillah Karim, Rami Nashashibi, Amir Al Islam
    - Deepening Research On Cross Sector Partnerships in the Middle East, Oct. 24-26, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Sonia Ospina; Bethany Godsoe
    - Producing Public Value Through Cross Sector Social Relationships, Oct. 25, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Ali Al Rahbi; Jamila Khanji; Mohammad Al Jawdar; Bethany Godsoe
    - The View from Somewhere: Discourse in the Humanities, Oct. 27, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Philip Weinstein
    - Building Apps For the Social Good of the Arab World, Oct. 30, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Sana Odeh
    - Christo and Jeanne-Claude, Nov. 14, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Christo
    - Science and Society Innovation, Nov. 15-16, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: John J. Healey
    - Nationalization of the Workforce in the GCC Countries III, Nov. 20-21, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Samira A. Atallah
    - From MR Imaging of Diffusion in White Matter Tracks to Brain Interconnectivity, Nov. 23, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speaker: Andrew Kiruluta
    - Death of a Salesman: Theater Mitu, Nov. 24, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Rubn Polendo
    - Too Creative for Science?, Dec. 05, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Ahna Skop
    - A Billion Minds and Lives: Global Strategies and Local Solutions for Integrated Health Care, Dec. 11-12, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Gary S. Belkin, Lloyd I. Sederer, Jrgen Untzer
    - Mental Health as a Global Priority, Dec. 11, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officators/Speakers: Amna Al Marzouqi, Vikram Patel, Shekhar Saxena, Gary S. Belkin
    - Translating Ahmad Faris al-Shidyaq's Leg over Leg, Dec. 13, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Humphrey T. Davies, Michael Cooperson, Philip Kennedy, James Montgomery, Shawkat Toorawa, Rebecca Johnson
    - World Literature and Translation, Dec. 14-15, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Paulo Horta, Philip Kennedy
    - European Representations of Islam in the Era of Crusade, Dec. 15, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Suzanne Akbari
    - West Meets East: A Composer's View, Dec. 18, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Gerald Levinson
    - The Future of International Climate Action, Jan. 09, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Richard Stewart
    - Poised Between the Past and the Future: The Sheikh Zayed Mosque in Abu Dhabi, Jan. 12, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Robert Hillenbrand
    - Uncanny Valley: On the Digital Animation of the Face, Jan. 15, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Lawrence Weschler
    - Woolly Wonder: A Yarn about Coral Reefs, Global Warming, Hyperbolic Geometry, and Community Art Practice, Jan. 17, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Margaret Wertheim
    - Coral Reefs of the Gulf, Jan. 17-19, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: John Burt
    - Towards Sustainable Management of a Shared Marine Environment, Dec. 18, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Peter Sale
    - Design Meets Philosophy, Feb. 05, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Roberto Casati
    - What is Single Shot Cinema?, Feb. 08, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Leonard Retel Melmrich
    - Enhancing Economic Development through Technology: Focus on Africa and Other Developing Regions, Feb. 12-13, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Yaw Nyarko, Lakshminarayanan Subramanian (CTED: Center for Technology and Economic Development)
    - Somalia, the Horn of Africa, and Food Security, Feb. 12, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: His Excellency Jerry Rawlings
    - Circadian Rhythms Writ Large and Small, Feb. 14, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Michael Rosbash
    - Genomics and Systems Biology II, Feb. 14-16, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Claude Desplan, Michael Purugganan
    - The Future of Global Governance, Feb. 20, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Stephen Stedman
    - The Use of Force, Crisis Diplomacy, and the Responsibilities of States, Feb. 21-22, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Bruce D. Jones (CIC - Center on International Cooperation)
    - Traditional Arabic Music: Between History and Modern Performance, Feb. 27, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: George Sawa, Suzanne Meyers Sawa
    - Opportunities and Challenges Facing Arab Women in Computing, Mar. 5, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Deanna Kosaraju
    - The Ramayana Theater Mitu, Mar. 8-10, 2012 (Box E-records)
    - Uniting the Humanities and Technology through Engineering to Improve Quality of Life, Mar. 11, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Lou-Chuang Lee
    - Networking the Cloud: Enabling Enterprise Computing and Storage, Mar. 18, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: K. K. Ramakrishnan
    - The Climate Mosaic: Understanding the Hidden Patterns of Clouds, Winds, and Weather, Mar. 20, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Olivier Pauluis
    - The Road to the White House 2012, Mar. 25, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Robert Shrum, Steve Schmidt, Rogan Kersh
    - The Case for Liberal Education, Mar. 28, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Anthony Kronman
    - Being Bedouin: Past and Present, Apr. 4, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Dawn Chatty, AbdAllah Cole, Sulayman Khalaf, Nathalie Peutz
    - Pathways to Social Change: Women Leading the Way, Apr. 16, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: May Al Dabbagh, Ruba Yousef Al Hassan, Maryan Bin Fahad, Farah Foustok
    - Bridge of Knowledge: From East to West, Apr. 19, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Alastair Hamilton
    - Linguistic Illusions: Where You See Them, Where You Don't, Apr. 23, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Colin Phillips
    - Ramlila of Ramnagar: Who is Rama?, Apr. 25, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Richard Schechner
    - Water, Expert Knowledge, and the Politics of Sustainability, Apr. 30, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Steven Caton
    - Multimedia on Mobile Devices, May 2, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Wolfgang Effeisberg
    - Next Generation Multimedia Research and Development, May 2-3, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Sunil Kumar, Abdulmotaleb El Saddik
    - Why Nations Fail: The Origins of Power, Prosperity, and Poverty, May 8, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: James Robinson
    - Numbers in Nature, Arts, and Architecture, May 21, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Itamar Procaccia
  - AY 2012-2013
    - How Non-Arab Muslims View the Arab World, Sept. 12, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: James Zogby, Hassan Fattah
    - Habitat Degradation on Coral Reefs, Sept. 16, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Morgan Pratchett
    - Sisters: A conversation with Nadia Benchallal, Sept. 27, 2012 (Box E-records)
    - The (In)Visible Reality Beneath, Oct. 02, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Angela Palmer
    - Folding Paper: Visual Art Meets Mathematics, Oct. 08, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Erik Demaine
    - Under Color of Authority: Terror, Intergroup Violence, and the Law, Oct. 11, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: James Sidanius
    - From Pearls to Oil, Oct. 14, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Mark Beech, David Heard, Philip Kennedy, Nick Cochrane-Dyet
    - A Dream Play Theater Mitu, Oct. 17, 2012 (Box E-records)
    - Friendship in the Classical World, Oct. 17, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: David Konstan, Phillip Mitsis
    - Materials for Tomorrow's World: Nanoporous Coordination Polymers, Nov. 06, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Sir Fraser Stoddart
    - The Music of the Arabic Renaissance, Nov. 08, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Salah Allam, Bassam Al Sattar, Oussama Abdel Fattah, Mustafa Said, Momahmed Zahireldine, Neil van der Linden
    - Photographs: Living Representations of Our Past, Present, and Future (MEPPI - Middle East Photography Preservation Initiative), Nov. 11, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Debra Hess Norris, Nora Kennedy, Shamoon Zamir
    - Crosstown Crossroads: Historic Preservation and Creative Place-Making, Nov. 21, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Todd Richardson
    - Sila Abu Dhabi 2012, Young Voices of Abu Dhabi: Imagining Tomorrow's Solutions, Nov. 24, 2012 (Box E-records)
    - Where the Sidewalk Ends: Informal Urbanism in Dubai, Dec. 03, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Yasser Elsheshtawy
    - Boom Cities: Urban Development in the Arabian Peninsula, Dec. 03-04, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Claire Beaugrand, Amlie Le Renard, Pascal Menoret, Roman Stadnicki
    - A Revolution in Healthcare: Systems and Proactive P4 Medicine, Dec. 05, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Leroy Hood
    - Is "Engagement" Dead? The US after 2012, Dec. 09, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: James Traub, Jules Coleman
    - Library of Arabic Literature, Dec. 09-12, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Philip Kennedy
    - Caliphs and their Consorts: Translating Anecdotes and Poetry, Dec. 12, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Julia Bray, the Editors of the Library of Arabic Literature, Shawkat M. Toorawa
    - Fantasies for Flute and Piano, Dec. 15, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Celina Charlier, Eshantha Peiris
    - Opening a Window on the Extreme Universe, Dec. 17, 2012 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Julie McEnery
    - The Geography of Progress: Cities in a World of Seven Billion, Jan. 16, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Richard Florida
    - Evolution and Rational Agency, Jan. 20, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Geoffrey Sayre-McCord
    - Metaethics, Jan. 20-22, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Nishi Shah, Matthew Silverstein
    - Literary and Culinary "Adab" in Arab Culture, Jan. 22, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Annia Ciezadlo, Philip Kennedy
    - Music and Science: What Could Modern Genomics Teach Us about Beethoven?, Jan. 29, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Nikolaus Rajewsky
    - The Elusiveness of the Tablighi Jamaat, Feb. 05, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Barbara Metcalf
    - Shadow Money, Shadow Parties, and the Future of American Democracy, Feb. 10, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Heather Gerken, Jules Coleman
    - Syria and the Return of Great Power Politics, Feb. 14, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Juan Cole
    - The World and its Challenges in 2013: A Conversation with Gordon Brown, Feb. 17, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: The Right Honorable Gordon Brown MP, Robert Shrum
    - What Does Your Genome Say about Who You Are?, Feb. 18, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Brenda Andrews
    - Genomics & Systems Biology III, Feb. 18-19, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Claude Despian, Michael Purugganan
    - Hackathon for Social Good in the Arab World, Feb. 24, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Sana Odeh
    - Organ Transplants, Islam, and Human Dignity in Egypt, Feb. 28, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Sherine Hamdy
    - Mathematical Myths and Misconceptions, Mar. 03, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Michel Broue
    - The Alpine Iceman: Understanding Our Human Past through Science, Mar. 05, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Gilberto Artioli
    - Culture and Identity, Mar. 10, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Sultan Al Amimi, Aisha Bilkhair, Mohamed Kanoo, Manish Pandley, H.E. Jose Eugenio Fernandez-Salarich Valderrama, Salem Brahimi
    - Big Data Systems, Applications, and Privacy, Mar. 10-11, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Yousif Asfour, Jonathan Chao, Torsten Suei, Kang Xi
    - African Women Write the Nation: A Conversation with Susan Andrade, Mar. 12, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Susan Andrade, Aisha Al Kaabi, Awam Amkpa, Judith Miller
    - Musical Rhythm: Cross-Disciplinary and Multi-Cultural Perspectives, Mar. 18-21, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Juan Bello, Carlos Guedes, Robert Rowe, Godfried Toussaint
    - Musical Diversity in Concert, Mar. 21, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Akshay Anantapadmanabhan, Celina Charlier, Carlos Guedes, Patti Kilroy, Dafnis Prieto, Robert Rowe, Siraj Mohammed Zaki
    - Design and Technology of Integrated Systems, Mar. 26-28, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Sunil Kumar, Ozgur Sinanoglu, Ramesh Karri, Kaushik Roy
    - Reflections on the Past, Present, and Future of Semiconductor Electronics, Mar. 26, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Mark Lundstrom
    - The Rahbani Legacy A Path of Bees, Mar. 27, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Ghazi Kahwaji, Hala Nohra, Oussama Rahbani, Henry Zogheib
    - The Original Music of the Emirates, Mar. 30, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Ali Abeid, Takht Al Emarat, Neil van der Linden
    - Should We Engineer Life?, Apr. 1, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Arthur Caplan
    - Zeb and Haniya, Apr. 4, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Zeb Bangash, Haniya Aslam, Zain Ali, Patrick Farrell, Zeeshan Mansoor, Kamran Paul, Michael Winograd
    - Art-Making and the Avant- Garde in the UAE, Apr. 6, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Mohammed Kazem, Jessica Mein, Maya Allison
    - Abu Dhabi Reads: Across the Empty Quarter, Apr. 11, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Electra Street, A Journal of the arts and humanities at NYUAD
    - Baroque Pearls, Apr. 13, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Celina Charlier, Fabio Pellegatti
    - Arab Culture and European Renaissance: A New Perspective on a Neighboring World, Apr. 14-15, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Jan Loop, Justin Stearns
    - Cultural Encounters between Europe and the Arab World through the Ages, Apr. 14, 2013 (Box E-records)
    - Hidden Motions Lurking in the Deep: A Modern View of the Restless Ocean, Apr. 17, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Shafer Smith
    - Global Institutions for Climate Finance, Apr. 21, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Robert Bradley, Richard Stewart
    - The Future of Climate Change, Apr. 22, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Arunabha Ghosh, Gilbert Metcalf, Athena Ballesteros
    - Poetry and Historical Memory, Apr. 24, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Christopher Merrill, Natasha Trethewey
    - Women's Leadership in the UAE: Negotiating Global and Local Perspectives, Apr. 29, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Sheikh Hussein Al-Banawi, Nawal Al Hosany, Shamma Al Jaberi, Sylvia Maier, May Al Dabbagh
    - Women's Advancement in the UAE: Strategies for Success, Apr. 29-30, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: May Al Dabbagh, Vera Jelinek, Carolyn Kissane, Sylvia Maier
    - Experimental Art and the Arab World, May 1, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Kenneth Goldsmith; Tiffany Malkooti
    - Between Hormuz and Malacca, circa 1599, May 6, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Jorge Flores